these Chechens They fight or don’t
эти чеченцы Они воюют или не
fight, they fight on horseback And where are the dead
воюют воюют коне А где погибшие
Kadyrovites Well, I don’t know them, I
кадыровцы Ну они есть я не знаю я я учёт
don’t keep records I don’t keep records, look at Vanya Wagner
Не веду я вот смотри у Ване У Вагнера
has his own there and the cemetery of the
есть свои там и кладбище
Wagnerites you’re
вагнеровцев ты
dead
погибший Здравствуйте
Hello Hello What’s your name
Здравствуйте Как Вас зовут
John How again John John  And you are just
Джон Как ещё раз Джон Джон А Вы прям
John by birth or Well, or Well, it’s like
Джон по рождению или Ну или Ну это как
Or it’s like, well,
Или это как бы ну
John John in the passport John I have
Джон Джон в паспорте Джон У меня же
Russian person No, I’m half Russian,
русский человек Нет я наполовину русский
half Scots And yes, and then I have
наполовину шотландец А да а тогда
no questions, I’m half, well, I have a
Вопросов нет у меня полу ну у меня
complex story, my mother is
сложная история получается у меня мать
from Russia, from Rostov, and my father is from
из России из Ростова а отец он из
Scotland. And why is the story complicated
Шотландии А почему пому история сложна
because, as it were, during the Olympics, my
потому что как бы во время Олимпиады
father was in
отец был в
this is what I understood No, it’s great that people
этом я понял Не ну классно люди
met No he didn’t leave, he
познакомились Не он не уехал он
met his
познакомился с
mother and started living I was born in Rostov But
мамой начали жить Я родился в Ростове Но
this was the Soviet Union I was born in the first year of
это Советский Союз был я воде перго года
birth somehow Well, it turns out my father
рождения как-то Ну и получается отец он
went to Scotland here  to Scotland here
ездил в Шотландию сюда в Шотландию сюда
and then all this when it turns out
а потом в се сем когда получается уже
Perestroika was already possible to take my mother
Перестройка была можно было забрать маму
and he took us we moved to Scotland to
и он забрал мы переехали в Шотландию в
Edinburgh well, super yes I don’t know Who I am
Эдинбург ну супер да я я не знаю Кто я
Yes, my mother is Russian from Rostov, my father is
Да у меня мама русская из Ростова папа
Scots who I am You just
шотландец кто я Вы просто когда
imagine  John and speak in pure
представляете Джон и говорите на чистом
Russian they laugh like it just
руском ржут типа
appeared right away I already
сразу сразу возник Я уже я уже мне
came across some of these bloggers there
попадались какие-то вот эти там блогеры
didn’t believe me I showed them my passport Well
мне не верили я им паспорт показывал Ну
like
типа
Well for
Ну ради
Bova’s sake My name is Viktor  I understand the name is
Бова зовут Меня Виктор зовут понял
Victor And this is really from birth
Виктор А это по настояще от рождение
Victor
Виктор
and I was
и я так
joking about
пошутил
you where are you from on May 9 just born
са Вы откуда сами 9 мая просто родился
from Lugansk from Lugansk This is where Russia
из Луганска из Луганска Это где Россия
Ukraine is now I don’t
Украина сечас Я не
know at all in the know there is something crossing
знаю совсем в курсе там что-то переходит
some territories Kursk Lugansk they are
одни территории Курск Луганск они
changing Everything is there  I know, well, Lugansk since
меняется Всё там я знаю Ну Луганск ещё с
2014, by the way, I have it there. Which
2014 года как бы у меня кстати там Какой
flag is shining here on which side they
флаг светится тут с какой стороны мня
show me the British British, I
показывают британский британский по я
installed VPN Ukraine, talked with Ukrainians
ставил VPN Украину общался с украинцами
and then  canceled something, they told me
и потом что-то отменил мне вот говорили
that my Ukrainian flag was lit, I couldn’t
что у меня светился украинский флаг я не
change it. I mean, from behind, it’s not in chatroulette,
поменять В смысле сзади не в чатрулетке
but I realized here, I see that the
а я понял тут я вижу что светится
Briton is glowing, I don’t
британ тоже не
understand either, I think how the Ukrainian one wasn’t removed,
пойму думаю как там не убрался
and it’s not even Ukrainian. Well, in
украинский Да ещё не не украинский Ну по
theory  I’m asking for Ukraine Oh, I’m
идее у меня запита на Украину О я Я же
telling you, I put Ukraine, I talked with
говорю я ставил Украину общался с
Ukrainians because when you put
украинцами потому что Когда ставишь
Britain, you don’t come across them, they
Британию они тебе не попадаются они
choose either Russia or Ukraine A
выбирают либо Россию либо Украину А
now I wanted to deliver to Russia and I can’t
сейчас хотел Россию поставить и не могу
change the type it doesn’t give Well, I don’t know, well, you
поменять типа не даёт Ну не знаю ну км
work for miles I’m an entrepreneur in Lugansk
работаете Я предприниматель в Луганске
there, yes yes, what are
там да да а что
you doing? Well, I sell all sorts of goods
предпринимаете Ну продаю всякие товары
for
для обслуживания
office maintenance, well, which the office needs, conditionally,
офисов ну которые необходи офисе условно
there are erasers, pencils, household chemicals,
там ластики карандаши бытовая химия
stationery. In short, I understand a wide range  Well,
канцеля А короче широкий спектр понял ну
in short, yes, everything you need in the office That’s how it is,
короче да Всё что нужно в офисе Вот как
and Lugansk is there, in my opinion. The war has been going on
а Луганск это ж там по-моему Война идёт
since 1914. That’s what Trade is like
с четырнадцатого года Это ж там какая
there
там
Well, we’re not working, what I
Торговля Ну есть не работаем что я я
heard on TV is that Lugansk
слышал по телевизору что там Луганск
was bombed there in 8 years, there are no people there, like,
разбомбили за 8 лет там людей нету типа
well, no, how they beat him,
ну не ну как его побо били
but well, again, all these
но ну как бы опять же таки эти все
objects have already been generally restored,
объекты уже в целом восстановлены
most of them, almost all of them. What was
большинство почти все А что там
it that was bombed there?  Well, how can it be
разбомбили такого Ну как можно
restored if I look at
восстановить если я смотрю вот в
Mariupol, Bakhmut was bombed,
Мариуполь разбомбили бахмут разбомбили
they were bombed Well, how can they be restored and like Lugansk
их Ну как их восстановить и как Луганск
if it was bombed, how can it be
если его разбомбили как его можно
restored like Mariupol? Well, the
восстановить как Мариуполь Ну здание
Mariupol building was not restored either.
Мариуполь тоже ничего не восстановили
No, I talked, I talked to people,
не Не ну я я общался я общался с людьми
they live in Krasnodar now, they are from
они вот в Краснодаре сейчас живут они из
Mariupol. Yes, they showed me photographs, they
Мариуполя Да они мне фотографии
said they went to
показывали говорили они ездили в
Mariupol there, and their house still stands
Мариуполь туда да дом ихний стоит до сих
with a crack like that, they built
пор с трещиной такой там построили
a couple of houses there like To show
какой-то пару домов типа Чтобы показать
that  like construction is going on and that’s it Well, not really
что типа стройка идёт и всё Ну не совсем
I was in Mariupol Yes there is Well there in the
Я был в Мариуполе Да там есть Ну там по
center of the city when about
центру города когда про
that is there Well yes you can see that the
то есть там Ну да вот видно да е что
city hasn’t recovered from the war but on  in the
город е не откачал от войны но на
outskirts, new neighborhoods are already being built there.
окраинах там уже строят новые
And if people
квартала А если люди по кто туда
come there to live for whom it’s all
приезжает жить для кого это всё
being built. Well, that means they’re building it for someone, I
строит Ну значит для кого-то строят я же
don’t know, I’m
не знаю я ри
half a million people somewhere, there are decrees. Yes, now it’s
полмиллиона людей гдето указы Да сейчас
left there because I watched
там осталось потому что я смотрел
a program. A Russian journalist went there.
передачу Российская журналистская ездила
-there are less than 100,000 people left
там что-то осталось меньше 100.000 людей
in this in Mariupol, well, I haven’t
в этом в Мариуполе вот ну я по голо не
counted them by the count here, I haven’t Well, yes, there are,
пересчитывал тут я не Ну да Там же есть
Well, these services keep records and it turns out
Ну учёт ведут эти службы и получается
If  400,000 left Who went to Russia Who went
Если 400.000 по уезжала Кто в Россию Кто
to Ukraine for whom these houses are now being built
в Украину для кого сейчас строят эти
for visiting Uzbeks and Tajiks not Well,
дома для приезжих узбеков таджиков не Ну
perhaps for those who have lost their housing as an
возможно для потерявших жильё как
option
вариант
That is, they were bombed here and here they are In short,
То есть тут разбомбили и тут им Короче
some kind of incomprehensible garbage And you And
какая-то фигня непонятная А у вас А у
you are building housing in Lugansk
вас в Луганске строят
Yes, and it
жильё Да и
’s free, no, at the same pace as in
бесплат не не Такими темпами как в
Mariupol, of course, well, it’s faster there.
Мариуполе конечно ну там побыстрее Ну
Well, build too. Yes, they give it out for free, they
тоже строи Да бесплатно
don’t give it  Well, again, this is
раздают не дают тем Ну опять же таки это
not for everyone Well, it’s not like you
не всем подряд Ну не то что ты прил руку
raised your hand and said I want an apartment, well,
поднял и сказал я хочу квартиру вот ну
that is, this is some kind of hero there, let’s say
то есть это каким-то геро там допустим
there to the families of
там семьям
military personnel of fallen servicemen E
военнослужащих погибших военнослужащих Э
some civil servants and those who are needed Yes
каким-то госслужащим да которые нужны Да
there teachers there  conventional
там преподавателям там условных там
martial arts there, for example, or dancing
единоборств к примеру или танцев
Look, I saw Well, I don’t know how
Посмотри я я видел Ну не знаю как
Lugansk Donetsk - it also
Луганск Донецк - это тоже там где-то
happens somewhere near you, yes Well, I don’t really know
возле вас получается да Ну я я не совсем
this geography, I know that there is Lugansk
эту географию знаю знаю что есть Луганск
there is Donetsk, but I don’t know or they  close
есть Донецк но не знаю или они близко
or far not close it’s somewhere
или далеко нет близко это где-то
kilometers seen
километров видел
uh they’re honoring there they’re doing IDM and the girls
э чествуют там идм заниматся и девушек
are going wild
беспредельничает
Where in Donetsk it’s right
Там где в Донецке прям
Yes no no But no it’s all nonsense
Да не нету Та не это это всё глупости
because well we had them too and what
потому что ну и у нас тоже были и что
they are
они
Well yes okay Well okay Well  That is,
Ну да нормально Ну нормально Ну То есть
I wouldn’t say there, again, you
я бы не сказал бы там опять же таки
know, if we judge there Yes, here’s a
знаешь если мы рассуди там Да вот
Chechen Yes, but how to judge About the whole people,
чеченца Да а как рассудить О всём народе
yes Well, any nation has its good
да Ну в любом народе есть свои хорошие
people and bad ones Yes, well  that is, there were bad ones
люди и нехорошие Да ну то есть нехорошие
in Lugansk since you were so careful.
были в Луганске раз ты так аккуратно Да
Yes, well, there
ну ну
were probably bad ones too, yes.
нехорошие наверное тоже были да
Well, something to me is that you somehow became afraid of the word
Ну что-то мне что ты как-то от слова
Chechens.
чеченцы стал
Yes, no. Absolutely not. Well, well, well,
бояться Да не Абсолютно нет Ну а что ну
I just know, I’ll think about this
Я просто знаешь я задумаюсь над этим
question. You  but he immersed me in mental
вопросом Ты же меня погрузил в мысленные
Memories Yes, well, what happened there Yes, well,
Воспоминания Да ну что там было Да ну
somehow, well, no, well, I talked with the Chechens Well,
как-то ну ну нет ну я с чеченцами
yes, normal guys, well,
общался Ну да нормальные ребята ну
guys, people like I talked with the military man, he
ребята люди как я общался с военным он
Wagner, he said that these Akhmata
вагнером он говорил что эти Ахмата
says That's what he said directly Yes, that
говорит Вот он прямо так и сказал Да что
Wagner is fighting there, Russian boys are fighting And
Вагнера воюют там русские пацаны воюют А
these guys are just filming TikToks, he says,
эти типа только снимают тиктоки говорит
and
и
they are far from the front line, they keep
они далеко от линии фронта держат там
shops there, bazaar points, in short, they put it on the counter,
магазины точки базары короче на счётчик
and that's it, they're all getting rich, there's no
ставят вот и всё обогащаются все нет
such thing  definitely not on the meter, look
такого точно нет на счётчик смотри
why, here he is, as he told me, I also
почему вот он он мне как сказал я тоже
say that it’s unlikely And he says Look,
говорю что навряд ли А он говорит Смотри
if we take it  Wagner How many
э если мы возьмём Вагнер Сколько
died to
погибших
the Wagnerites And where are the Chechen dead
вагнеровцам А где чеченские погибшие
they say where are the Kadyrovites dead and I don’t
говорят где кадыровцы погибшие и я не
know what they get
знаю что иму
from look if we’re talking about the guard Yes
от смотри если мы говорим про гвардию Да
Kadyrov there, well, the guys are very cheerful
Кадыров там ну прям ребята очень бодрые
and very serious and extremely cultured with the
и очень серьёзные и крайне культурные с
population, that is, they are just in general and
населением то есть они прямо вообще да
if anyone is just  dialed Yes, well, there are
если кого просто набирали Да уже ну там
already different people there, you understand,
уже разные люди ты понимаешь
yes, well, that is, how does someone behave?
да ну то есть как бы кто как себя ведёт
I don’t know Yes, but I can’t understand again,
Я не знаю Да но я не могу понять ещё раз
look if these  Chechens Are they fighting or not
смотри если эти чеченцы Они воюют или не
fighting,
воюют
and where are the dead
а где погибшие
Kadyrovites? Well, they are there, I don’t know, I
кадыровцы Ну они есть я не знаю я я учёт
don’t keep records. Look, alas. Wagner has
Не веду Вот смотри ува У Вагнера есть
his own there, and a cemetery there are
свои там и кладбище
dead Wagnerites. I have no idea, this is for me, this is a
погибшие Понятия не имею вот мне это вот
guy for me, well, it’s not like, look for
мне парень ну это же не то что смотри
me  from Edinburgh It’s not very visible Yes,
мне из эдинбурга Не сильно видно Да я
then I communicate, I’m interested, I
потом общаюсь мне интересно я с
communicate with Ukrainians, I communicate with Russians, these are
украинцами общаюсь с россиянами вот эти
all the topics that I’m interested
все темы и мне
in.  Wagner has Yes, there are several
У нас есть У Вагнера Да несколько
cemeteries where Wagner’s fighters are buried.
кладбищ где вот похоронены бойцы Вагнера
Yes, there is a record, there is a memorial by Wagner.
Да есть учёт есть мемориал
Who died there from the Wagnerites and
вагнером Кто там погиб из вагнеровцев и
there is a record of them all? Yes, how many 50,000 have
их есть учёт все Да сколько там 50.000
already died there and that’s all he says, but Akhmat
уже погибло и всё а говорит а у Ахмата
doesn’t have a single dead person, so he
нет ни одного погибшего вот он так и
says so and  says Find, I was looking too,
говорит и говорит Найди я искал тоже
like yes, who died from the Akhmat regiment, how many
типа да кто погиб из полка Ахмат сколько
of them are
их
not, I don’t
не я не
know this question You asked
знаю на этот вопрос Ты мне его задал у
me, I don’t have an answer Well, I don’t
меня нет ответа Ну я не
know, someone  probably died somewhere Well, not
знаю кто-то где-то наверное погиб Ну не
probably, but 100%
наверное а 100%
well, somewhere I won’t tell you, in short,
ну где-то я не скажу тебе короче
some mythical ones, these
какие-то мифические эти
dead Well, I don’t know, I don’t know, I can’t
погибшие Ну не знаю не знаю не могу
answer this
сказать на этот
question, well, Akhmatov, again, you
вопрос вот ну Ахматов опять же таки
understand this, you know how to reason about
понимаешь это знаешь как рассуждать вот
this  let’s say the nation is bad, but that’s
это там допустим нация плохие да это же
wrong, just like he says that
неправильно так же как и говорит что
like Kadyrovites they are all bad No, there are a
типа кадыровцы они все плохие Нет там
lot of very cheerful people there, that is, Kadyrovites are not
куча очень бодрых то есть кадыровцы не
all bad Yes, absolutely no And for some reason
все плохие Да абсолютно Нет А почему то
there is even a good one among Kadyrovites
среди кадыровцев есть даже хороший
someone yes Well, why even well, you see, they’re
кто-то да Ну почему даже ну ты вишь они
not all
не все
bad No, well, they are, again, I’m
плохие Не ну они опять же таки я же
talking about those people I came across,
говорю те люди с которыми я сталкивался
who are exactly there as personnel, and even before the
которые именно там кадровые да ещё до д
second year they were straight up as personnel Yes, they are
второго года они прям кадровые Да они
very, very cool, serious guys
очень очень классные серьёзные ребята
and they definitely won’t pull the toilets Well,
и унитазы они точно не будут тянуть Ну
this is the Sun Well, it’s a myth Well, that is, it turns out that
это ВС Ну миф Ну то есть получается да
even among Kadyrov’s men there are normal ones, it
даже среди кадыровцев есть нормальные
turns out Yes, yes, well, why Well,
получается Да почему Да же Ну почему Ну
damn, well, these are also people,
блин ну это же тоже люди
these are the same people as you and me Well, they are
это такие же люди как мы с вами Ну они
normal people  Yes, the
нормальные люди Да
military, they act on orders and in
военные они действуют по приказу и в
general Well, that is,
целом Ну то есть как
at least with those people with
бы по крайней мере с теми людьми с
whom I came across Yes, there are no questions for them,
которыми я сталкивался Да вопросов к ним
they are very, very good guys And
Нет они очень очень хорошие ребята А
look, by the way, I also saw a
смотри я видел ещё
video, it
кстати видео
turns out that some guy from Volgograd is
получается какой-то парень из Волгограда
like-  then Nikita I don’t remember his last name, he
как-то Никита его не помню фамилию он
was doing something with the
что-то там какую-то акцию делал с
Koran and he was detained by the police and
кораном и его задержала полиция и вместо
instead of being tried in Rostov
того чтобы ему его судить в в Ростове
Volgograd Volgograd he
Волгограде Волгограде он да то его
came  Kadyrov's men came and took him to
приехал кадыровцы приехали забрали его в
Grozny during the season and Kadyrov's son came there.
Грозный в сезо и там приходил сын
Fifteen-year-old, this
Кадырова Пятнадцатилетний этот
Eh, like Adam Kadyrov, and
Ээ как он Адам Кадыров и на камеру
beat this Russian guy on camera, how do you feel about
избивал этого парня русского как ты к
this?
этому
Well, I don't welcome this on the
относишься ну я это не приветствую с
one hand from a legislative point of
одной стороны законодательной точки
view Yes, but on the other hand, burn the Koran
зрения Да но с другой стороны Коран
it’s wrong It’s not so clear that it’s
сжигать это неправильно Не так ясно что
wrong, look, to steal everything
неправильно всё смотри воровать
It’s wrong there, but it is if there are laws of the
Неправильно там но есть если есть законы
Russian Federation Well, here in
Российской Федерации Ну у нас вот в
Britain Yes, we can’t do that If  someone
Британии Да нельзя вот наме Если кто-то
committed an offense, they can’t take him
сделал правонарушение его не могут взять
and, in short, the governor comes and knocks
и короче прийти губернатор типа и сбить
him down, you know.
его понимаешь
Well, I don’t know
Ну я не знаю
how the
как
United States beat someone, came to a pre-trial detention center and beat
США с бил кого-то приходил в СИЗО и бил
someone, well, the son of the president’s son is
кого-то не ну Сын сын президента
fine there. What are the sons of presidents in the
нормально там Что сы сын президентов в
USA?  so that he would come to prison and beat someone.
США чтобы пришёл в тюрьму и кого-то бил
Well, there is no way to sniff the tracks. So
Ну нюхать дорожки себе там нет Так
wait, look, we don’t know whether he sniffs or
подожди смотри я мы не знаем нюхает или
not to sniff, but there is no such thing that he would come; in short, they
не нюхать но нету такого чтобы он пришёл
gave him the short term to beat up the dude A
ему дали короче на избиение чувака А
that's why beating a dude is worse better
вот что избиение чувака это хуже лучше
than there
чем там
let's say no
допустим нет
if Look Here in Britain
если Смотри Вот у нас в Британии
Yes there is criminal punishment Yes, why do
Да есть уголовное наказание Да а почему
you have no criminal punishment for beating a Russian guy
у вас за избиение русского парня
by a Chechen
чеченцем нету уголовного
I again, I don’t
наказания я опять же таки я не
support this whole process
поддерживаю это этот процесс весь
Yes but in general  humanly Yes Despite the
Да но в целом по-человечески Да Несмотря
fact that I am a
на то что я
Christian Well, it’s just like that on the street
християнин Ну вот так вот чисто на улице
Yes, if we figure it out, what if I
Да если мы разберёмся да что если я
saw that a person was burning the Koran
увидел бы что человек сжигает Коран
Yes, this is generally
Да это вообще
wrong You’re doing this  Why do you
Неправильно ты это делаешь Зачем ты
offend people, it doesn’t matter, it doesn’t matter, it doesn’t matter. For
обижаешь людей неважно смотри неважно
example, why. For example, for the one who
Вот например почему Например за тот Кто
burned the Bible. Yes, they don’t take him away; in short, in
сжёг Библию Да его не забирают короче в
Yaroslavl they don’t beat up a Russian, yes. And
это в Ярославле не избивают русский да А
then Kadyrov’s people, like, took a Russian guy.
тут кадыровцы типа взяли русского парня
Well, that is, what am I getting
Ну то есть я к чему веду что я не могу
at?  bibles Well, I’m saying there was
понять ато в библи Ну я говорю были там
someone there over the Bible or
кто-то над библией или плохо
spoke badly about the Bible, there’s a lot of
высказывался про Библию та куча есть
that, there’s a lot of that, well, you don’t have any
такого Да куча возьми Ну у тебя же нет
examples. Well, you’re just you’re just  Look, I’ll
примеров Ну ты просто ты просто Смотри я
tell you why because Russian Russians,
скажу почему потому что русские русские
it seems to me, are second-class in Russia,
как мне кажется в России второго сорта
far from even second-class Yes, Chechens,
далеко даже не второго Да чеченцы
for example, a Russian against a Chechen will
например русский против чеченца ничего
not say anything, a Chechen against a Russian will say
не скажет чеченец против русского скажет
yes, if you’re afraid, you see, you’re rzsh,
да если и ты же боишься видишь ты ты рзш
you’re afraid of Kadyrov, a Chechen, I see you’re
ты боишься Кадырова чеченце вижу ты
afraid And
боишься А
why I don’t know why
почему я не знаю почему
not Yes, I’m telling you that, again,
нет Да я тебе говорю что опять же таки
those people with whom I talked are
те люди с которыми я общался они
normal, yes, well, but how about you, look at
нормальные да хорошо а как ты вот смотри
Ramzan Kadyrov in public  on camera on
Рамзан Кадыров публично на камеру на
television announced a blood revenge on two
телевидение объявил кровную Месть двум
Senate deputies on two senators Yes,
депутатам Сената двум сенатором Да
the State Duma, how do you react to this
Госдумы как вот ты на это реагируешь
and he directly embodied it, look at the idea
а он её прям воплотил смотри в я иде в
that I am a lawyer, I will say according to Russian
том что я юрист я скажу по Российскому
legislation Yes, this is called a
законодательству Да это называется
threat of murder, if you threaten
угроза убийства если Ты угрожаешь
murder, this is already  criminal offense
убийство это уже уголовное преступление
Even if you did not
Даже если ты не
carry out the threat to kill, this is already an
воплотил угроза убийством это уже есть
independent
самостоятельное
crime; they stated that for their
преступление него заявили что за свою
life they look, yes. This is a crime
жизнь чи Смотри да Это преступление
that does not require an applicant. For example,
которое не требует заявителя Например
if someone says that  he’s Putin’s Yes, you
если кто-то говорит что он Путина Да вот
don’t need Putin to write a statement against him,
не нужно чтоб Путин на него написал
you know, for the person to be
заявление понимаешь чтобы человека
brought to
привели к
justice Well, if they stole from you
ответственность Ну если у тебя украли
Then you need a statement, yes If you were
Тогда нужно заявление да Если тебе
beaten somewhere, you need a statement Yes And such
побили где-то нужно заявление Да А такие
things E, you don’t need a
вещи Э не нужно
statement Well, let’s say Well, how does
заявление Ну допустим Ну как так
that happen then  it turns out that Kadyrov
получается то есть получается Кадыров
can do whatever he wants in Russia and
может делать всё что хочешь в России и
bring his son to a pre-trial detention center so that he can
своего сына приводить в СИЗО чтобы он
beat him in short and hard place. Nothing will be announced to
бил короче и кровно месте Объявлять ему
him. Well, you know, it seems to me that this is what happens in every
Ну ты знаешь мне кажется так в каждой
country, and even in
стране и происходит и даже
the UK and even in the USA and even in
Великобритании и даже в США и даже в
which  -That  South Africa in the UK,
какой-то южной афри в Великобритании
tell me where in the UK some
скажи где в Великобритании какое-то
official
должностное лицо
was declared or threatened with murder, he
объявлялось или угрозу убийствами ему
didn’t have anything for it, tell me I said it
ничего за это не было скажи я сказал мне
seems to me or but it seems to me I understand And it seems to me
кажется или а кажется понял А мне
and it seems to me that you are just
кажется а мне кажется что ты просто
Kadyrov and his brother Why do I need them?
Кадырова и его брату А зачем мне их
they threaten me personally, not just are you
что они мне угрожают лично не просто ты
afraid to speak out loud? Yes, because
боишься вслух говорить Да потому что
in short, I’m telling you my opinion. I
короче тебе это говорю своё мнение Я
’m afraid to speak out loud, I’m my opinion. That
боюсь говорить вслух я своё мнение То
is, more honestly, there are both good
есть как бы честнее есть и и хорошие
people and bad people, and what kind of bad people there are in
люди и плохие люди а Какие плохие люди в
Chechnya,
Чечне
well, all sorts of  and in the Volgograd
есть ну всякие как и в Волгоградской
region as well as in the Khan Autonomous
области как и В ханском автономном
Okrug Well name
округе Ну наме
lo
ло
di For example, I don’t know what else What other
ди Например я не знаю приме что ещ Какие
bad people are there Well, well, some
ещ есть плохие люди Ну ещё ну какие-то
I don’t know
там я не знаю
there were scammers there Yes, let’s say there for
там разводилы там Да допустим там к
example Well
примеру Ну они
they are Moshe and  there and ve I watched
Моше они есть и там и ве Я смотрел
the news and
новости да
there are Russian Soldiers Rodri Russian
там российские Солдаты родри российски
soldiers it was so that means among Kadyrov’s men there
солда было тако значит среди кадыровцев
is also
тоже есть
Mad But you open
Мад А вот открываешь
it Look, here you take your participant  and went
Смотри вот берёшь участник свой и пошло
participant Pony on the Internet, yes, and of
участник Поня в интернете да а уголовные
course there were criminal cases,
дела тож конечно были уголовные дела
so the question turns out to be
то вопрос получается
there too, yes, wait, wait, let’s go back
тоже есть да стой подожди давай вернёмся
to this topic in Ukraine there were criminal
к этой теме в Украине были уголовные
cases, and Ukraine I’m from Britain dude
дела причём Украина Я из Британии чувак
no yes What does this have to do with what I’m saying in Russia, he did
нет да Причём тут я говорю в России убил
n’t kill in  Ukraine and this is that a member of his own in
не в Украине и это что участник сво в
Russia is someone someone, here I am, then there’s something
России кого-то кого-то вот я вот есть та
else that turns out, it means that among
дальше что да то получается значит среди
Kadyrov’s men there are also those
кадыровцев тоже есть такие
who
которые
rob this, people understand  And here among the
грабят это люди понял Причём тут среди
British there are also people who understood yes,
британцев тоже есть люди ко понял да да
well, that is, look, among the Kadyrovites there are
ну то есть смотри среди кадыровцев есть
yes. It turns out that no, you’re not
да Получается что нет ты же не ко Верка
talking about Verka, that is, as if among the Kadyrovites
речь то есть как бы среди кадыровцев
among the
среди
British, yes, that is, among the Kadyrovites
э британцев да то есть среди кадыровцев
as well as among the British
как и среди британцев
there are you, focus focus  you do On the nation This is
есть ты фокус фокус делаешь На нации Это
wrong nation Kadyrovtsy there is no such
неправильно нация кадыровцы нет такой
nation Kadyrovtsy the British exist but
нации кадыровцы британцы есть а
Kadyrovtsy not I didn’t say I say
кадыровцы не я не сказал Я говорю
Kadyrovtsy Look, I understand correctly that
кадыровцы Смотри я правильно понимаю что
both among the British and among
как среди британцев так и среди
Kadyrovtsy
кадыровцев
there are, I can say among the British
есть вот я могу сказать среди британцев
there are, you can say that among
есть ты можешь сказать что среди
Kadyrovtsy there are, they are punished everywhere, right,
кадыровцев есть их карают везде прави
well, look, I say there are among the British,
вот Ну смотри я говорю среди британцев
you can say among Kadyrovtsy, I
есть ты можешь сказать среди кадыровцев
think
есть Думаю
yes, I think you  you can say, I’m saying that
да Думаю ты можешь сказать Вот я говорю
among the British there are, I don’t personally know any
среди британцев есть я не знаю Лично ни
of them Well, I personally don’t know of any of them,
одного Ну я лично ни одного не знаю
first of all, they’re not Chechens, they’re people
это в первую очередь не чеченцы это люди
Good  look, let's look, among the
Хорошо смотри давай так смотри среди
British there are men who are men
британцев есть мужчины которые мужчи
among the Kadyrovites, there are also men
среди кадыровцев тоже есть мужчины
who have
которые
never heard of men about such cases, I don’t know.
мужчин о таких случаях не слышал не знаю
Well, there are such everywhere, among all
Ну есть такие всюду есть среди всех
nations, among the Kadyrs there are
Наций среди Кадыров есть
such. Well, about such cases in their ethnic group, it’s
такие Ну о таких случаях в их этносе это
like there are certain ethnic
же как бы есть определённые этнические
nuances Yes, well,
нюансы Да
I don’t know, I’m not ready to say right away What
ну не знаю не готов сказать сразу Какие
ethnic nuances like, well, I don’t understand This is
этнические нюансы типа ну не понял Это
Islam so about this, what and what is
ислам так об этом что а что а в
possible in Christianity or what a man Well, I
христианстве можно или что мужика Ну я
can or can’t,
можно или нельзя
but they have certain  their own kind of
но у них определённые свои какие-то
ethnic bonds Yes, well, the insides of the Russians are
этнические скрепы Да ну нутри у Россиян
also bonds, but the Russians in prisons
тоже скрепы но россияне в тюрьмах
turn out to be men, so damn, everyone
мужиков получается так это блин это все
knows that. Are you kidding me, you
знают Ты что прикалываешься
know, the whole prison subculture
зна в вся субкультура тюремная вокруг
revolves around this or do you
этого крутится или ты
want to? Well,
хочешь А ну
inside it turns out, look, among the
внутри то получается смотри среди
Kadyrovites there are also those  which
кадыровцев также есть те которые
in Well, like among the Russians there are among the
во Ну как среди русских есть среди
British there are and among the Kadyrovites No,
британцев есть а среди кадыровцев Нет
they are like some kind of Gods I don’t know, maybe
они что какие-то Боги Я не знаю возможно
Well, you agree that among everyone among
Ну ты согласен что среди каждого среди
everyone  ethnicity there are people who are
каждого этноса есть люди которые
men Among the whole world, I would say from the
мужчин Среди всего мира я бы сказал сди
whole world yes that is, that is, people
всего мира да то есть то есть люди
who are men are among the British there are
которые мужчин есть среди британцев есть
among the Russians there are among the Kadyrovites
среди русских есть среди кадыровцев
Why do you have such a focus on the
Почему у тебя фокус такой на
Chechens Look, I can’t why
чеченцах Смотри я не могу почему ты я
can you tell me about my Britain  Yes, we
могу про свою Британию сказать Да у нас
have people who are men. This is wrong,
есть люди которые мужчин Это неправильно
yes, but they exist in Russia. You
да но они есть в России такие есть ты
can say about the Russians about the British,
можешь сказать про россиян про британцев
but you can’t say about Kadyrov’s men,
но не можешь сказать про кадыровцев
why? Well, at least again.
почему Ну по крайней мере опять же таки
I didn’t have such news, yes. So
у меня новостей таких не было да Так у
you didn’t have such news about the British either,
тебя и про британцев не было таких
but you can say that in
новостей но ты можешь сказать да что в
Britain there
Британии такие
is such, not Well, again, about the European Union
есть не Ну опять же таки про Евросоюз У
I have a
меня есть
funny one, in short, I’ll tell you You’re just
смешной короче чу я тебе скажу Ты просто
afraid that the Chechens are shorter than you  and
боишься что тебя короче чеченцы и
that’s why
поэтому типа
you’re not like Well, why am I? I’m telling you, I haven’t seen anything like that.
ты не Ну почему я Я же говорю я такого
Perhaps they are good, but
не видел Возможно они есть хорошо а вот
look. Why why are there such
смотри Почему почему ходят такие
pictures that Kadyrov is like he’s an ass,
картинки что Кадыров как бы он осла вот
I’ve seen pictures like this. Where does such
я видел такие картинки Откуда такой
banter come from? Yes, I  how do I know? Well, there is no smoke
стёб Да я откуда знаю Ну вот нет дыма
without fire. Well, people can’t just
без огня Ну не могут просто так люди не
come up with something that Putin gave and with Kadyrov
придумает что Путин дала а с Кадыровым
there are pictures that are bad. Why is
есть картинки что сла Почему
this so? Well, this is not a question for me. Well,
так Ну это не ко мне вопрос Ну вот вот
someone someone started it somewhere for some reason
кто-то кто-то запустил где-то почему-то
Come on, sir Well, this picture is here people and
Да ну сри Ну эта картинка она вот люди и
I see many of the Russians who I
мне вот многие из россиян которые вот я
talked to a Russian nationalist from Perm,
с русским националистом общался из Перми
he said that the Kadyrovites are so he
он говорил да что кадыровцы они так он
Nava know why this is his personal opinion
Нава знаю почему это его чное мнение
good
хоро
I  I ask, is it true that
Я спрашиваю Правда ли что правда ли что
Kadyrov’s people
у кадыровцев
practice animals with donkeys, but don’t
практикуется животными с ослами но мне
tell me not to sleep with
говори не сном с
sheep? Well, some kind of EU. Honestly, with those
баранами Ну какая-то ес Честно ну с теми
Chechens with whom I talked, we
чеченцами с которыми я общался мы эти
definitely didn’t discuss these topics, that is, they didn’t
темы точно Не обсуждали то есть они не
bother you,
лезли тебя
no, well,  They probably attacked you, but they
не не Ну на тебя наверно полезли но на
didn’t, that is, even
меня нет то есть даже
inspire me. It seems to me, Well, because I’m a
воодушевить Мне кажется Ну потому что я
Cool kid, like, of course, and you’re
Классный пацан да типа конечно а ты
cool, based on such a conversation. Well,
прикольно исходя из такого разговора Ну
you  as if you are more you you are just in this
ты как бы больше ты ты ты просто в этом
conversation so much you are so
разговоре настолько ты настолько Да
Yes it was just so funny
настолько это просто было смешно
Come on, I didn’t understand that I’m not British
Давай так не понял что я не британец
write to my Telegram right now axis VN
пись на мий Telegram прямо зараз ось ВН
apok tse more and more respectfully YouTube taking
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through the skarg ODS in your ban  and I
нас через скарг ОРВ в твый бан и дуже
don’t show too many videos to people at all times, I don’t
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams for this
показуе информация про стрими Тому для
reason, Mali is operational  The link
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
will be written directly at the same time, but in the meantime, there is a video on the
пишиться прямо зараз а пок там в
telegram okrim video schetezh
телеграме окрим видео ще теж
tsikava and korisna information and we are guilty
цикава и корисна информация и мы повинни
of you trimati postiyny operational
з вами тримати постийний оперативный
link
звязок
nezalezno in that chi show you about it
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава украини
subscribe L
подпишись L